# MARCELO LEOPOLD

PHP Developer



Boston



www.marceloleodev.com



Graduated in Civil Engineer University of Belo Horizonte, Brazil.

I learned to program by myself and have been experience for more than 10 years as a PHP Systems Developer, I was part of several advanced teams like Analysts, DBAs, Diagrammers and Architects, most of the time using Agile Methodologies. I'm always open to learn new things.

### **WORK EXPERIENCES**

#### PHP Developer

August 2017 - Present

Boston, Massachusetts, USA

www.turnupweb.com

### **Construction Supplies Negotiator**

August 2016 - July 2017

MRV Engenharia

Pernambuco, Brazil

After completing college in Civil Engineering, I was hired by the company "MRV Engenharia" for complex necociations of machinery and equipment for construction in the area of the State of Pernambuco, Brazil. Advanced Excel Skills.

#### Web System Developer

MaxMilhas

June 2014 - August 2016

Belo Horizonte, Minas Gerais, Brazil

I was one of the first developers of the MaxMilhas.

Complex system that connects people who want to sell airline miles with people who want to buy airline tickets.

I was part of the PHP team and System Architect.

After a year I was one of those responsible for the website's Financial System (Online Payment and Internal Financial Control of the company).

#### **PHP Developer**

September 2012 - June 2014

Aceleradora de Empresa

Belo Horizonte, Minas Gerais, Brazil

PHP Developer, ExtJs4, Zend Framework and Doctrine 2, Unit Tests using PHPUnit and DBUnit. Development a big system with remote developers in 3 different towns, we work together to make the project. System to "Fundação de Apoio à Universidade Federal" (Federal University Support Foundation).

# **PHP Developer**

October 2009 - August 2012

useInternational

Belo Horizonte, Minas Gerais, Brazil

System Analyst, PHP Developer, CSS support, MySQL support, Selenium Test using PHP.

# PHP Developer

February 2008 - June 2009

Algar Tech

Belo Horizonte, Minas Gerais, Brazil

I was part of the virtual store development team for the newspaper "Estado de Minas" using PHP, JavaScript, MySQL.

As a system maintenance of "SEMAD - Secretaria de Estado de Meio Ambiente e Desenvolvimento Sustentável" (State Secretariat for the Environment and Sustainable Development) using JAVA.

### Web Developer (PHP, ASP, Javascript)

September 2006 - October 2007

■ Bolt Brasil Comunicação Digital

Belo Horizonte, Minas Gerais, Brazil

Development and maintenance on several systems and websites, including managers and online stores.

## EDUCATION

### English Second Language

SCALE - Somerville Center for Adult Learning Experiences

Somerville, Massachusetts, USA

(2020 - Present)

### **English Second Language**

Everett Adult Learning Center

Everett, Massachusetts, USA (2018 - Present)

### Bachelor's Degree, Civil Engineering

Centro Universitário de Belo Horizonte

Belo Horizonte, Minas Gerais, Brazil (2010 - 2015)

## **Computer Engineering**

Universidade FUMEC

Belo Horizonte, Minas Gerais, Brazil (2009 - 2010 LOA)

# LANGUAGES

Portuguese (Native)

English (Limited working proficiency)

#### SKILLS

#### Technical

PHP

jQuery / NodeJS / ExtJs4

HTML5 / CSS3

Laravel 6 / Symfony

Docker / LaraDock

GIT

MySQL / PostgreSQL

Doctrine 2

TDD / PHPUnit / DBUnit

Selenium

OOP

MVC

PSR

#### **Professional**

Open Mindedness

Creativity

Teamwork

Problem-Solving

Critical Thinking

Willingness to learn